{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dili","incorrectAnswers":["Yerevan","Nuku'alofa","Kigali"],"question":"What is the capital city of Timor-Leste?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does Lord Voldemort appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Coral","incorrectAnswers":["Diamond","Gold","Silver"],"question":"In Western society, what is the traditional gift for a 35th wedding anniversary?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Octopus","incorrectAnswers":["Pelican","Squid","Albatross"],"question":"A giant Pacific __________ can fit its entire body through an opening no bigger than the size of its beak.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Puerto Rico","incorrectAnswers":["Portugal","Peru","Latvia"],"question":"In which country is pitorro a popular drink?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Screwdriver ","incorrectAnswers":["Hammer","Spanner","Wrench"],"question":"Which cocktail shares its name with a tool?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Carded","incorrectAnswers":["Combed","Washed","Sheared"],"question":"What term is used to describe the process of preparing wool fibers before they are spun?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Antelope","incorrectAnswers":["Bison","Elk","Deer"],"question":"What large herbivore sleeps only one hour a night?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Copenhagen ","incorrectAnswers":["Paris","Rabat","Istanbul"],"question":"Which Capital City Might You Associate With A Statue Of A Mermaid?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Pittsburgh Penguins","incorrectAnswers":["Pittsburgh Lions","Pittsburgh Canucks","Pittsburgh Flames"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Pittsburgh?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Albert Camus","incorrectAnswers":["François-René de Chateaubriand","Anatole France","Guy de Maupassant"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Stranger'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Carly Simon","incorrectAnswers":["Tina Turner","Sheena Easton","Shirley Bassey"],"question":"Who sang the theme tune to the James Bond. Movie 'The Spy Who Loved Me'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Whiskey","incorrectAnswers":["Beer","Wine","Rum"],"question":"What type of alcoholic beverage is bourbon?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Chad","Uruguay","Lithuania"],"question":"Ankara is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Banjo","incorrectAnswers":["Fiddle","Ukelele","Accordion"],"question":"Name The Guitar Like Instrument With A Circular Belly Of Streched Parchment","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Julius Caesar","incorrectAnswers":["Augustus","Nero","Caligula"],"question":"Which Roman figure's name is used to refer to the calendar system we use?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lemurs","incorrectAnswers":["Tarsiers","Bushbabies","Gibbons"],"question":"Pottos and tarsiers are closely related to what small primates from Madagascar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"West Germany","incorrectAnswers":["France","United States","Mexico"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1974 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Seasons in the Sun","incorrectAnswers":["Genius of Love","867-5309 - Jenny","Bust a Move"],"question":"Terry Jacks had a one hit wonder in 1974 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Everest","incorrectAnswers":["Kilimanjaro","Elbrus","Denali"],"question":"What is the world's highest mountain?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer released the song 'Halo'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Lion King","incorrectAnswers":["Aladdin","Beauty and the Beast","Mulan"],"question":"Which Disney movie features the song 'Can You Feel The Love Tonight', written by Elton John and Tim Rice?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cobb salad","incorrectAnswers":["Waldorf salad","Caesar salad","Nicoise salad"],"question":"What is the name of the salad that includes lettuce, bacon, chicken, eggs, and blue cheese?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Nanny","incorrectAnswers":["A Sow","A Lioness","A Hen"],"question":"A female goat is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dustin Hoffman","incorrectAnswers":["Gene Hackman","Tom Hanks","Edward James Olmos"],"question":"Who won the 1988 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Raymond Babbitt in Rain Man?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Aristotle","incorrectAnswers":["Denis Diderot","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Anaxagoras"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Happiness is the highest good'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Adolf Hitler","incorrectAnswers":["Josef Stalin","Joseph Goebbels","Hans von Tschammer und Osten"],"question":"Who was supposed to present Jesse Owens his 100 metre Gold Medal at the Berlin Olympics?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Chirac","incorrectAnswers":["Macron","Hollande","Sarkozy"],"question":"Which Pompidou protege and recent French president organized talks with trade unions after France's 1968 mass demonstrations?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The most beautiful girl in the world","incorrectAnswers":["A pack of smokes","His heart","A cup of kindness"],"question":"What Was Charlie Rich Looking For In 1973?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"7","incorrectAnswers":["8","6","12"],"question":"What Do The Opposite Sides Of A Standard Dice Always Total?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The effects of climate on living organisms","incorrectAnswers":["Friction and lubrication","Christianity","Wine and winemaking"],"question":"What is Bioclimatology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1965","incorrectAnswers":["1969","1973","1961"],"question":"In Which Year Did A Soviet Cosmonaut Make The First Spacewalk?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The UK","incorrectAnswers":["The USA","Argentina","France"],"question":"Which country administers South Georgia, a last stop before Antarctica?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Shang","incorrectAnswers":["Liu","Ming","Yi"],"question":"What was the first Chinese dynasty?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Kabuli Pulao","incorrectAnswers":["Frikadeller","Ema Datshi","Masala Dosa"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Afghanistan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Annie","incorrectAnswers":["Cats","Chicago","Les Misérables"],"question":"What musical features the songs 'Little Girls' and 'It's The Hard-knock Life'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chad","incorrectAnswers":["Togo","Equatorial Guinea","Ghana"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Nigeria?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cate Blanchett","incorrectAnswers":["Amy Adams","Sandra Bullock","Judi Dench"],"question":"Who won the 2013 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Jasmine in Blue Jasmine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"May the Force be with you.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"You’re going to go through life thinking that girls don’t like you because you’re a nerd. And I want you to know, from the bottom of my heart, that won’t be true. It’ll be because you’re an a**hole.\"","\"Shane. Shane. Come back!\"","\"Elementary, my dear Watson.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Star Wars'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Brad Pitt","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Hanks","Anthony Hopkins","Al Pacino"],"question":"Who won the 2019 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Cliff Booth in Once upon a Time...in Hollywood?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Strange Case of Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde","incorrectAnswers":["The City & the City","Frankenstein","The Hunchback of Notre Dame"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Mr Utterson the lawyer was a man of a rugged countenance, that was never lighted by a smile; cold, scanty and embarrassed in discourse; backward in sentiment; lean, long, dusty, dreary and yet somehow lovable.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Baby Got Back","incorrectAnswers":["867-5309 - Jenny","What's Up","Bitter Sweet Symphony"],"question":"What song did Sir Mix-A-Lot have a hit with in 1992?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A dreidel","incorrectAnswers":["A menorah","A Torah scroll","A shofar"],"question":"Which of these is a four-sided spinning top, played during the Jewish holiday of Hanukkah?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eminem","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Drake","Ludacris"],"question":"Which American rapper, producer and actor released the studio album 'The Marshall Mathers LP'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Onion ","incorrectAnswers":["Pepper","Tomato","Garlic"],"question":"Chives are a member of which family of vegetables?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Gabon","Belgium","Lithuania"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Freyja","incorrectAnswers":["Frigg","Idun","Freyr"],"question":"What is the name of the Norse goddess of love and beauty?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Magnum Opus","incorrectAnswers":["Big Deal","Corpus Christi","Super Maestro"],"question":"What term is used to describe the most important or best work that a writer or artist has produced?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Almonds","incorrectAnswers":["Peanuts","Hazelnuts","Pistachio Nuts"],"question":" What kind of nuts are used in marzipan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bourbon","incorrectAnswers":["Scotch","Rye","Irish whiskey"],"question":"What type of whiskey is Old Rip Van Winkle, a brand made in Kentucky?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cough","incorrectAnswers":["Headache","Nausea","Weight gain"],"question":"Which of the following is the main symptom of bronchitis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Blitz","incorrectAnswers":["The Raze","The Mortar","The Blaze"],"question":"What name was refers to Nazi Germany's bombing raids against Great Britain in World War II?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Hurt Locker","incorrectAnswers":["Avatar","The Blind Side","District 9"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2009?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jaws","incorrectAnswers":["Grease","In the Heat of the Night","The Searchers"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Captain Quint'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Landslide","incorrectAnswers":["Tsunami","Firestorm","Stampede"],"question":"What word is used when a candidate receives an overwhelming majority of votes in an election?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Marley and the Wailers","incorrectAnswers":["Bob Marley and the Bombs","Bob Marley and his Blues Band","The Swinging Bobs"],"question":"What was the name of Bob Marley's band?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Marilyn Manson","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'Mechanical Animals'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Blue","Yellow","Red"],"question":" What colour is creme de menthe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Philadelphia Eagles","incorrectAnswers":["Philadelphia Saints","Philadelphia Fire","Philadelphia Thunder"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Philadelphia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Portugal","incorrectAnswers":["Morocco","Andorra","France"],"question":"The old Roman province of Lusitania is now called ____________. ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Portland","incorrectAnswers":["Seattle","Vancouver","Boise"],"question":"Which city in the USA contains both The Columbia River and The Willamette River?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Mika"],"question":"Which British musician performed under the alter ego 'Ziggy Stardust'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Cat Stevens","incorrectAnswers":["Joni Mitchell","Patti Smith","The Ramones"],"question":"Who Released The 70's Album Entitled 'Tea for the Tillerman'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cow","incorrectAnswers":["A Ewe","A Worker","A Bitch"],"question":"What is a female whale known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Perspiration","incorrectAnswers":["Saline","Lactate","Water"],"question":"What is the name of the salty, watery fluid secreted by sweat glands?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"People's Republic of China","incorrectAnswers":["Tajikistan","Kyrgyzstan","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Pakistan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Denver Broncos","incorrectAnswers":["Denver Hornets","Denver Marlins","Denver Indians"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Denver?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Green","Orange"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Georgia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Swimming","incorrectAnswers":["American Football","Sailing","Tennis"],"question":"Which sport is associated with The FINA World Championships?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dunkirk","incorrectAnswers":["Calais","Le Havre","Brest"],"question":"'We shall fight on the beaches', is a quote from Winston Churchill immediately following the evacuation from which French port?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Inglourious Basterds","incorrectAnswers":["Hotel Rwanda","Snatch","Cool Hand Luke"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'During World War II, a group of Jewish U.S. soldiers plan to assassinate Nazi leaders.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Amy Adams","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Emma Thompson","Kirsten Dunst"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in films including Man of Steel and American Hustle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Myanmar","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Singapore","Bangladesh"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Thailand?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Paris","incorrectAnswers":["Strasbourg","Lyon","Nantes"],"question":"What is the capital of France?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Greece ","incorrectAnswers":["India","Morocco","Russia"],"question":"Where Might You Be Offered Ouzo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A brood","incorrectAnswers":["A kindle","A field","A clowder"],"question":"What is the word for a group of hens?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"To Kill a Mockingbird","incorrectAnswers":["Cool Hand Luke","The Elephant Man","The Lion King"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A lawyer in Depression-era Alabama defends a black man against an undeserved rape charge.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shaped pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Ribbon pasta","Tubular pasta","Strand pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is fusilli?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Martina Hingis","incorrectAnswers":["Serena Williams","Maria Sharapova","Steffi Graf"],"question":"Which Female Tennis Star Was Handed A Two Year Ban After Testing Positive For Cocaine At Wimbledon In 2007?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Supertramp","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","The Hollies","Hawkwind"],"question":"Which Band Released The Song \"Breakfast In America\"? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mark Wahlberg","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Fiennes","Brian Cox","Michael Douglas"],"question":"Which actor has had roles in films including The Departed and Ted?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Stethoscope","incorrectAnswers":["MRI Scanner","Forceps","Insulin Pen"],"question":"What instrument do doctors often have around their necks?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Species","incorrectAnswers":["Habitat","Size","Discoverer"],"question":"Dinasaur Names Are In 2 Parts , The First Part Being The Genus. What Is Denoted By The Second Part?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Arizona","incorrectAnswers":["Colorado","New Mexico","Nevada"],"question":"Which US state is directly south of Utah?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","incorrectAnswers":["Nigeria","Switzerland","Vietnam"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Green with a vertical white band on the left side. The green section contains a white crescent and star.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dialysis","incorrectAnswers":["Chemotherapy","Physiotherapy","Radiation"],"question":"What process is used when kidneys are not working properly?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Michael Keaton","incorrectAnswers":["Simon Pegg","Toshirō Mifune","Roger Moore"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in both Spider-Man: Homecoming and Birdman?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The United States of America","incorrectAnswers":["Canada","Australia","India"],"question":"Which of the following countries was founded during the 18th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Nathaniel Hawthorne","incorrectAnswers":["Robert E. Howard","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Twice-Told Tales'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Nietzsche","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Baruch Spinoza","Jean-Paul Sartre"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'God is dead! He remains dead! And we have killed him.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Bysshe Shelley","H. Rider Haggard","Robert Louis Stevenson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'On the Origin of Species'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Prince","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Jackson","Stevie Wonder","Marilyn Manson"],"question":"Who Legally Adopted A Symbol To Replace His Name In 1993?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Silver","incorrectAnswers":["Gold","Iron","Copper"],"question":"What metal corresponds to the Spanish term \"plata\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Catcher","incorrectAnswers":["Pitcher","Guard","Steer"],"question":"What Is The Name Of The Player In Baseball Who Is Positioned Behind The Home Plate","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rice","incorrectAnswers":["Potato","Corn","Fish"],"question":" What is Japanese \"sake\" made from?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mark Wahlberg","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Fiennes","Brian Cox","Michael Douglas"],"question":"Which actor has been in films including The Departed and The Fighter?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Liège","incorrectAnswers":["Madrid","Zürich","Lyon"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Belgium?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","Thailand","China"],"question":"In which country would you find city of Kyoto?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Domain Name System","incorrectAnswers":["Data Network Server","Dynamic Network System","Data Name System"],"question":"In computer networking, what does DNS stand for?","difficulty":"hard"},